# Guilherme Branco Stracini

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

guilherme@guilhermebranco.com.br



+971 52 615 1060



linkedin.com/in/guilhermestracini



https://guilherme.stracini.com

### Summary

Software engineer, well experienced with C# .NET and Node.JS.

Work permit (no sponsorship required): Portuguese passport - European Union.

Currently working in Talabat (part of Delivery Hero), which is a delivery company in MENA, based in Dubai, as a backend software engineer, working with C# .NET, AWS (SQS, SNS, Lambda, S3, SSM, EC2), Microsoft SQL Server, Terraform, ArgoCD, CircleCl and other tools on QCommerce tribe (formerly Grocery tribe). Using TDD, DDD & SOLID principles and approaches.

Two years with financial background, developing a digital wallet, PIX/SPI (Brazilian Instant Payments system) and Open Banking / Open Finance integrations, direct contact with B2B clients, regulatory agencies, others banks and technical teams to provide the best solution for both sides! Using C# .NET Core, Node.JS, Microsoft SQL Server, RabbitMQ supported by DDD, SOLID, DRY & KISS.

I am excited to contribute my strengths and proficiency in innovation toward your team efforts. As an extroverted and personable communicator with a proven track record in technical writing, my focus on building strong professional relationships has been a valuable asset throughout my career.

Experience (in years):

12+ C# .NET

12+ Microsoft SQL Server

10+ MySQL

8+ Node.JS

7+ .NET Framework

7+ Elastic Search

6+ .NET Core

4+ AWS (Amazon Web Services)

3+ Azure

3+ RabbitMQ

3+ PostgreSQL

3+ Apache Kafka

#### Some projects I worked on:

- Food & Grocery delivery Shopping Experience & Order Fulfillment
- Product Information Management (PIM)
- Western Union integration/RPA for remittance across countries
- Digital wallet (payments, transfers, remittance, balance, statement, mobile top-up, credit card)
- PIX Brazilian Instantly Payments System (SPI/PIX BACEN)
- Open Banking Brasil BACEN
- Banking as a Service (BaaS)
- Microservices culture
- Distributed systems using RabbitMQ and Apache Kafka

- Gateway integrations with MaxiPago, Adyen and PayPal
- On boarding and Internet Banking projects for B2B customers
- VTEX e-commerce PaaS (integration)
- Sankhya (ERP) / SAP (ERP) (management, analysis, integration)
- Vitrine do Artesanato Digital digital video platform (development)
- Vitrine do Artesanato na TV digital video content portal (development)
- Canal do Artesanato subscription learning platform (development)
- Zendesk (integration)
- Database management
- Agile methodologies
- Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC)
- General web development
- Open Source Software (OSS) projects in C# .NET, PHP, Rust and JS/TS, available at https://github.com/guibranco

### **Experience**

## Software Engineer

talabat

Jan 2022 - Present (1 year 4 months)

Working on Grocery Shopping Experience squad (former FAST - Finding and Shopping Team squad)

- Improve search, offers and shopping experience in Grocery tribe / QCommerce tribe
- Migration from monolithic architecture to microservices architecture
- Building APIs and services with C# (.NET 5/6/7), Amazon SQS, SQL Server and PostgreSQL
- Configuration of backend for frontend (BFF) API gateway using KrakenD, Luna and GoLang
- DDD (Domain Driven Design) and TDD (Test Driven Development) approaches
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum over Jira

### Software Engineer

talabat

May 2021 - Dec 2021 (8 months)

Working on Grocery Fulfillment squad

- Improve quality of fulfillment process working together with all grocery tribe
- Migration from monolithic architecture to microservices architecture
- Item heartbeat / grocery catalog availability monitoring, providing pickers to set an item unavailable at handle & ship process
- Item replacement allowing customers, pickers and back office change unavailable itens on an order
- Robocalls, automated phone calls with Asterisk integration
- Building APIs and services with C# (.NET 5), Amazon SQS, Amazon SNS, Amazon Lambda, SQL Server and PostgreSQL
- DDD (Domain Driven Design) approach
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Jira

### Senior Software Engineer

Syndigo

Jun 2021 - Nov 2021 (6 months)

(Part-Time / Contract) Working on Customer Experience Hub (CXH) platform

- Integrations with Instacart and BestBuy
- Improve quality of code, fixing code smells and bugs
- Building APIs and services with C# (.NET Core 3.1/.NET 5), Azure Blob Storage, Azure Service Bus and SQL Server
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Jira and Azure DevOps

### Senior Software Engineer

FCamara Consulting & Training

May 2021 - Aug 2021 (4 months)

(Part-Time / Contract) Working for FCamara, in the Open Banking / Open Finance project

- Developing IdP (Identity Provider), DCR (Dynamic Client Registration)
- Developing White Label platform
- Integration with Banco Pan
- Building APIs with Node.JS, Cosmos Db, Azure Service Bus
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Azure DevOps

## Senior Software Engineer

The Bridge Social

Feb 2021 - May 2021 (4 months)

(Part-time / Contract) Working for Grace Kennedy (Jamaica & Caribbean area) client, developing:

- Remittance integration with Western Union
- Digital wallet system
- Building API and Services with C# (.NET Core 3.1 and .NET 5), using CosmosDB, Microsoft Azure Service Bus, Entity Framework Core, Dapper, Application Insights, RPA (Robotic Procedure Automation)
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Azure DevOps

https://www.gracekennedy.com/

### F Senior Software Engineer

**FARFETCH** 

Dec 2020 - May 2021 (6 months)

Working on Search & Scouts team:

- Development of improvements in the search services of the platform
- Development solutions using Kafka, Cassandra, C# (.NET Core), Elastic Search
- Working side-by-side with Data Scientists team providing data and schemes for our project
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Jira

## **bsz** Senior Software Engineer

Banco BS2

Mar 2020 - Jan 2021 (11 months)

Working on Special Projects team, part of Financial Services division

- Implementation of PIX/SPI (Brazilian Instantly Payments BACEN)
- Development of APIs and Services using C# .NET Core, Dapper, Entity Framework and DDD
- Architecture of the CORE PIX and Indirect PIX solutions inside the BS2 Bank
- Development of accounting system for Indirect PIX partners
- Development of distributed systems using RabbitMQ
- Deploy and development using Docker containers
- Supporting internal clients in integration process
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Azure DevOps

### bsz Middle Software Engineer

Banco BS2

Jul 2019 - Mar 2020 (9 months)

Working on B2B tribe, on API Banking squad

- Development of API banking product (https://devs.bs2.com) BaaS
- Development of open banking project
- Development of APIs using C# .NET Core, Dapper, Entity Framework and DDD
- Development of distributed systems using RabbitMQ
- Deploy and development using Docker containers
- Supporting clients in integration process
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Team Foundation Service (TFS)

### Middle Software Engineer

**C&A Brasil** 

Dec 2018 - Jun 2019 (7 months)

Working on e-commerce team, on refund/reversal squad.

- Development of integrations solutions using Zendesk, SAP, Oracle and other internal systems
- Automation of payment/refund process using Adyen gateway
- Automation of process using C# .NET Core
- Implement Elastic Search and Kibana for log & metrics in e-commerce team
- Develop new features and APIs using Node.JS (Express & HAPI)
- Develop of an unified library in C# .NET Core to be used internally by all teams, with commons & utils needs
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Jira

#### Project Development Coordinator

Editora Inovacao Ltda [Inovacao Media Brazil Group]

Jan 2016 - Nov 2018 (2 years 11 months)

Head of development in IT department. Managing developers team, agencies and associates.

- Development of services and APIs using C# (.NET Framework 4.7/4.8/4.8.1 and .NET Core 2.1)
- Implement SOLID principles
- Implement Apache Kafka and RabbitMQ for distributed systems process
- Implement Elastic Search and Kibana for log & metrics purposes

- Development of an internal search engine using data from Elastic Search (clients, orders and orders items)
- Deploy, evangelize and speech of continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD)
- Development of integrations solutions
- Development of RESTful APIs for mobile apps
- Coordinate the development of a CRM system
- DevOps culture
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Trello and RunRun.It

#### Software Development Analyst

Editora Inovacao Ltda [Inovacao Media Brazil Group]

Nov 2013 - Dec 2015 (2 years 2 months)

- Website development using ASP.NET C# .NET technology and MVC standard
- Web API 2 (C# .NET) web applications for user data access (via client web application) and restricted access data management of other internal projects
- Application development for product and order integration with the Smart Checkout / VTEX platform (SOAP web service / REST API)
- Payment gateway integration MaxiPago for subscription management
- Management of triggers and procedures in Microsoft SQL Server 2008 database
- Disaster Management / Automated Backup Plans on Microsoft SQL Server and Windows Server
- Automated backup with Amazon Web Service (AWS) S3

#### IT Analyst

Editora Inovacao Ltda [Inovacao Media Brazil Group]

Nov 2012 - Oct 2013 (1 year)

- Development of video portal using C# .NET language and MVC standard
- Development of service integration tool (SOAP web service and REST API) in C# .NET
- Monitoring and management of SQL Server database
- Requirements gathering
- Planning, modeling, implementation and process documentation ERP (Sankhya)

#### Information Technology Intern

Editora Inovacao Ltda [Inovacao Media Brazil Group]

Nov 2011 - Oct 2012 (1 year)

- Development of emails marketings campaigns (coding, triggering, reports)
- Formatting, maintenance and installation of micro-computers(Windows and Linux Ubuntu)
- General software installation and configuration
- Development of internal systems in VB.NET
- Development of system (VB.NET) for management of digital PBX (Total IP)
- Development of new features, tools and bug fixes in existing projects (classic ASP and PHP)

### Freelance Software Developer

Guilherme Branco Stracini ME

Jan 2007 - Present (16 years 4 months)

Acting as an independent consultant for some companies, worked on some projects per contract / deliveries.

- Development of portals and applications using: C# .NET, PHP, Node.JS, Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize
- One-off jobs, as a freelancer, using C# .NET, PHP, SQL, Node.JS and Rust
- Consultancy
- Integrations with VTEX (SaaS e-commerce platform) using C# .NET framework
- Integrations with Sankhya (ERP) using C# .NET framework and Microsoft SQL Server
- Integrations with payment gateways
- EBAOH project Products review platform with gamification

#### **Education**

#### Fatec FATEC São Caetano do Sul - Antonio Russo

Systems Analysis and Development Technologist, College - Technologist Jan 2011 - Dec 2013

Analyses, designs, documents, specifies, tests, implements and maintains computational information systems - 2800 hours - on-site classes.

#### señac Senac

Computer technician, Informatics

Jan 2008 - Jun 2010

Assemble and maintain microcomputers, install and configure networks and develop systems and websites - 1200 hours, on-site classes.

#### **CA** ETEC Professor Camargo Aranha

High School Diploma, High School/Secondary Diplomas and Certificates Jan 2007 - Dec 2009

#### **Skills**

Test Driven Development • Domain-Driven Design (DDD) • Microsoft SQL Server • C# • Design Patterns • Web Services • Software Documentation • Unit Testing • Continuous Integration • Continuous Delivery